Guide to the Mazzarella AIVS Collection of Librettos MSS.383
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mazzarella AIVS Collection of Librettos
1815-1966
Fales Library and Special Collections
American Institute of Verdi Studies
Mazzarella, John D.
MSS.383
5 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes.
The Mazzarella AIVS Collection of Librettos is comprised of John D. Mazzarella's collection of librettos for operas performed throughout Italy, and in London, Paris, Barcelona, and New York City in the 19th and early 20th centuries. The librettos were published between 1815 and 1966.
Scope and Content
The Mazzarella AIVS Collection of Librettos is comprised of librettos for operas performed throughout Italy, as well as London, Paris, Barcelona, and New York City, in the 19th and early 20th centuries. The librettos were published between 1815 and 1966.
Arrangement
The collection contains 63 series arranged alphabetically by composer. Within each series, librettos are arranged alphabetically.
Biographical Note
John D. Mazzarella served as Vice President and Eastern Manager of Community Concerts, a division of Columbia Artists Management, Inc. for thirty years. He also taught English at Bangkok Christian College for six years. Passionate about the arts and travel, Mazzarella was a long-time member of the American Institute of Verdi Studies. He died at the age of 71 in 2010.
Source:
John D. Mazzarella Obituary, The New York Times, August 28, 2010.
Historical Note
The American Institute for Verdi Studies (AIVS) is one of the world’s top research centers for the study of the life and works of Giuseppe Verdi. The idea for the AIVS emerged out of increased interest in Verdi research following the Fourth International Congress of Verdi Studies in 1974. Planning for the Institute began in 1974, with performers, scholars, critics, librarians, and Verdi enthusiasts agreeing to serve as advisors to the new organization. Officially founded on April 1, 1976, the AIVS is open to public membership and is a division of the Music Department at New York University. The AIVS sponsors and promotes conferences, lectures, and performances, and publishes the only English-language journal dedicated to Verdi, the Verdi Forum.
The Institute has organized three international conferences on Verdi studies, and in October 2013, the AIVS sponsored Verdi’s Third Century: Italian Opera Today, a conference at NYU to celebrate the bicentennial of Verdi’s birth and the legacy of his work. The AIVS Archive is located at the Elmer Holmes Bobst Library at NYU.
Source:
"Our History and Mission." American Institute for Verdi Studies. http://www.nyu.edu/projects/verdi/AIVSbackground.html
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Provenance
The collection of librettos is a bequest of John D. Mazzarella, a former member of the American Institute for Verdi Studies. Mr. Mazzarella bequeathed his materials to the AIVS in 2010. Mr. Mazzarella had acquired most of the items in his collection over the course of many visits to Italy. The AIVS transferred the materials to Fales Library in 2012.
Librettos (document genre for music).; American Institute of Verdi Studies; Mazzarella, John D.
- Series I: Alfano
  - Don Juan de Manara, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Librettist: Moschino, Ettore
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Ricordi
  - Il Principe Zilah, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Librettist: Illica, Luigi
  - Risurrezione, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Librettist: Hanau, Cesare
- Series II: Allegra
  - Ave Maria, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Librettist: Donini, Alberto
    Publication City and Publisher: Rome: Eredi Giovanni Artero
- Series III: Apolloni
  - L'ebreo, 1859-1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Librettist: Boni, Antonio
    Performance City and Venue: Piacenza: Teatro Comunitativo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1859-60
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Tito di Gio. Ricordi
- Series IV: Auber
  - La muta di Portici, [1836] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Librettist: Scribe, Eugène
    Performance City and Venue: Florence, Teatro alla Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1836
    Publication City and Publisher: Florence: Stamperia di F. Giachetti
  - La muta di Portici, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: Teatro alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1838-39
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: per Gaspare Truffi
- Series V: Balfe
  - The Bohemian Girl, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Librettist: Bunn, Alfred
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: Charles E. Tretbar
- Series VI: Baravalle
  - Andrea del Sarto, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Librettist: Ghislanzoni, Antonio
    Performance City and Venue: Turin: Teatro Carignano
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1890
    Publication City and Publisher: Turin: Tipografia L. Roux e C.
- Series VII: Barbier
  - Joan of Arc, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Translator: Lyster, Frederic
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: Fred. Rullman
    Note: Stage script only; no music present.
- Series VIII: Bellini
  - Beatrice di Tenda, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Librettist: Romani, Felice
    Publication City and Publisher: Naples: n.p.
  - Bianca e Fernando, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Librettist: Gilardoni, Domenico
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1829
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: per Antonio Fontana
  - I Capuleti e i Montecchi, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Performance City and Venue: Venice: Teatro La Fenice
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1830
    Publication City and Publisher: Venice: dalla Tipografia Casali
  - I Capuleti e i Montecchi, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1831-32
    Publication City and Publisher: Venice: La Vedova Casali Editrice
  - Norma, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: per G. Truffi e Comp.
  - Norma, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Il pirata, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1840
  - La sonnambula, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: Teatro Carcano
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1833
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: co' tipi di Omobono Manini
  - La sonnambula, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Performance City and Venue: Lugano: Teatro di Lugano
    Performance Season/Date: Fiera 1840
    Publication City and Publisher: Lugano: dalla tipografia di Giuseppe Bianchi
  - La sonnambula, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Edizioni Radio Teatrali Artistiche
    Editor: Bontempelli, Ettore
  - La sonnambula, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: unknown
  - La straniera, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan, Teatro alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1829
  - La straniera, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Performance City and Venue: Florence, Teatro della Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1830
    Publication City and Publisher: Florence: nella Stamperia Fantosini
  - La straniera, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: R. Stabilimento Tito di Gio. Ricordi
  - La straniera, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Edizioni "A. Barion" Della Casa Per Edizioni Popolari - S.A.
  - Zaira, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Performance City and Venue: Florence: Teatro della Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1836
    Publication City and Publisher: Florence: nella Stamperia di F. Giachetti
- Series IX: Berlioz
  - La damnation de Faust, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Librettist: Berlioz, Hector; Gandonniere, Almire; de Nerval, Gerard
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Casa Musicale Sonzogno (Societa Anonima)
- Series X: Bizet
  - Carmen, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Librettist: Meihac, Henri; Halevy, Ludovic
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: Cowdery & Prescott
- Series XI: Boito
  - Nerone, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Scope and Content
    Librettist: Boito, Arrigo
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: G. Ricordi & C.
- Series XII: Bottesini
  - Ero e Leandro, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Librettist: Gorrio, Tobia
    Performance City and Venue: Turin: Teatro Regio
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1878-79
    Publication City and Publisher: Turin: Tipografia Roux e Favale
  - La regina del Nepal, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Librettist: Tommasi da Sciacca, B.
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1880-81
- Series XIII: Braga
  - Caligola, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Performance Season/Date: Quaresima 1874
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: R. Stabilimento Ricordi
- Series XIV: Cagnoni
  - Il duca di Tapigliano, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: Teatro Castelli
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1875
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Stabilimento Musicale F. Lucca
  - Il duca di Tapigliano, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Francesca da Rimini, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Publication City and Publisher: Turin: Stabilimento Musicale Giudici e Strada
  - Papà Martin, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Stabilimento Musicale Ditta Francesco Lucca
- Series XV: Carafa
  - Il paria, 1826 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Librettist: Rossi, Gaetano
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1826
    Publication City and Publisher: Venice: dalla Tip. Casali Ed.
- Series XVI: Casati
  - Don Giovanni di Marana [ballo], 1843 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1843
- Series XVII: Catalani
  - Edmea, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1885-86
  - Edmea, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 10 1/2)
  - Loreley, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Librettist: D'Ormeville, Carlo
  - La wally, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1891-92
- Series XVIII: Charpentier
  - Louise, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Librettist: Charpentier, Gustave
    Performance City and Venue: New York: Manhattan Opera House
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: Charles F. Burden
- Series XIX: Cherubini
  - Medea, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Librettist: Hoffmann, Francesco Benedetto
    Translator: Zangarini, Carlo
    Performance Season/Date: 22 December 1909
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Romualdo Fantuzzi Editore
- Series XX: Cilea
  - Adriana Lecouvreur, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: Teatro Lirico Internazionale
    Performance Season/Date: November 1902
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Sonzogno
- Series XXI: Coccia
  - Caterina di Guisa, 1833 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1833
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: per Luigi di Giacomo Pirola
  - Clotilde, 1819 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1819
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: dalla Stamperia di Giacomo Pirola
  - La foresta di Hermanstad, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1817
    Publication City and Publisher: Turin: presso Onorato Derossi Stampatore e Librajo
  - La solitaria delle Asturie, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1838
    Alternate Title: o sia La Spagna ricuperata
- Series XXII: Dall'Argine
  - I due orsi, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Francesco Lucca
  - I due orsi, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series XXIII: Donizetti
  - Adelia, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Librettist: Romani, Felice; Marini, Girolamo Maria
    Performance City and Venue: Rome: Teatro Apollo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1841
    Publication City and Publisher: Rome: Tipografia Puccinelli
  - Anna Bolena, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Performance City and Venue: Barcelona: Gran Teatro del Liceo
    Performance Season/Date: 1858
    Publication City and Publisher: Barcelona: Imprenta de Tomás Corchs
    Alternate Title: Ana Bolena
  - Anna Bolena, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1840
  - Belisario, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Librettist: Cammarano, Salvadore
    Publication City and Publisher: Sesto San Giovanni: Edizioni A. Barion della Casa per Edizioni Popolari
  - Belisario, 1836 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Publication City and Publisher: presso Luigi di Giacomo Pirola
  - Belisario, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Performance City and Venue: Bergamo: Teatro Riccardi
    Performance Season/Date: Fiera 1837
    Publication City and Publisher: Bergamo: dalla Stamperia Mazzoleni
  - Belisario, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Publication City and Publisher: Turin: presso l'Editore Alessandro G. Rossi
  - Il borgomastro di Saardam, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1828
  - Don Sebastiano re di Portogallo, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Translator: Ruffini, Giovanni
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1847
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Tipografia Valentini e C.
  - Don Sebastiano re di Portogallo, 1865-1900 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Translator: [Ruffini, Giovanni]
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: R. Stabilimento Musicale Ricordi
  - Don Sebastiano re di Portogallo, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Performance Season/Date: Quaresima 1862
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Regio Stabilimento Nazionale Tito di Gio. Ricordi
  - Elisabetta, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Librettist: de Leuven, A.; Brunswik
    Translator: Guidi, S., and L. Masieri
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: Teatro di Santa Radegonda
    Performance Season/Date: Estate 1854
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: I.R. Stabilimento Nazionale Privilegiato di Tito di Gio. Ricordi
  - Fausta, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fausta, 1859-1860 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: coi tipi di Francesco Lucca
  - La favorita, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Performance City and Venue: Barcelona: Teatro del Liceo
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1862
    Publication City and Publisher: Barcelona: Imprenta de Tomás Gorchs
  - La favorita, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Librettist: Royer, Alphonse; Vaez, Gustave
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Casa Editrice Madella
  - La figlia del reggimento, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Librettist: Vernoy de Saint-Georges, Jules Henri
    Translator: [Bassi, Calisto]
  - La figlia del reggimento, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gemma di Vergy, 1839 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Librettist: Bidera, Giovanni Emanuele
    Performance City and Venue: Udine: Teatro della Nobile Società
    Performance Season/Date: Fiera 1839
    Publication City and Publisher: Udine: nella Tipografia di Liberale Vendrame
  - Gemma di Vergy, 1845 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Performance Season/Date: Fiera 1845
    Publication City and Publisher: Bergamo: dalla Stamperia Natali
  - Gemma di Vergy, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Performance City and Venue: Barcelona: teatro del Liceo
    Publication City and Publisher: Barcelona: Imprenta y Librería Politécnica de Tomás Gorchs
  - Gianni da Calais, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Alternate Title: 1841
  - L'ajo nell'imbarazzo, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Librettist: Ferretti, Jacopo
    Performance City and Venue: Padua: Teatro Novissimo
    Performance Season/Date: Estate 1828
    Publication City and Publisher: Padua: Tipografia Penada
  - L'elisir d'amore, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: Teatro alla Canobbiana
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1832
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: per Gaspare Truffi e Comp.
  - L'esule di Roma, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Linda di Chamounix, 1865-1900 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan and London: Regio Stabilimento Ricordi
  - Linda di Chamounix, 1865-1900 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Linda di Chamounix, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Lucia di Lammermoor, 1846-1847 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale e Quaresima 1846-47
    Publication City and Publisher: Venice: Tipografia di Giuseppe Molinari
  - Lucia di Lammermoor (with Esmeralda), 1839 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1839
  - Lucrezia Borgia, 1833 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1833-34
  - Lucrezia Borgia, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Performance City and Venue: Florence: Teatro alla Pergola
    Publication City and Publisher: [illegible]
    Notes: Title page torn: publication details missing
  - Lucrezia Borgia, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Performance City and Venue: London: Her Majesty's Opera (Theatre Royal, Drury Lane.)
    Publication City and Publisher: London: David's Musical Opera-Books, The Music-Publishing Company
  - Lucrezia Borgia, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Edizioni Ricordi
  - Maria Padilla [1 of 3], 1841 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Scope and Contents
    Performance City and Venue: Milano: Teatro Alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1841-1842
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Per Gaspare Truffi
  - Maria Padilla [2 of 3], 1841 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Maria Padilla [3 of 3], 1841 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Maria Padilla, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Performance City and Venue: Milano: Teatro del Mobile Condominio in Pavia
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1857-1858
  - Maria de Rudenz [1 of 2], 1837 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Performance City and Venue: Venezia: Gran Teatro La Fenice
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1837-1838
    Publication City and Publisher: Venezia: Tipografia Molinari Edit.
  - Maria de Rudenz [2 of 2], 1837 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Performance City and Venue: Venezia: Nuovo Gran Teatro La Fenice
  - Maria di Rohan, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Maria Stuarda, 1835 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Librettist: Bardari, Giuseppe
    Performance City and Venue: Milano: Reg. Teatro Alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1835-1836
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Per Luigi di Giacomo Pirola
  - Marino Faliero, 1838 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Librettist: Bidera, Emmanuele
    Performance City and Venue: Padova: Teatro Nuovo di Padova
    Performance Season/Date: L'autunno 1838
    Publication City and Publisher: Padova: Tipografia Penada
  - Marino Faliero, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Performance Season/Date: La Primavera 1840
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Per Gaspare Truffi
  - Olivo e Pasquale, 1871 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Performance City and Venue: Napoli: Teatri Filarmonica in piazza del Municipio
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1870-1871
    Publication City and Publisher: Napoli: Presso Giuseppe D'ambra
  - Parisina, 1837 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Performance City and Venue: Venezia: Nuovo Gran Teatro la Fenice
    Publication City and Publisher: Venezia: Tipografia Molinari Editrice
  - Parisina, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Performance City and Venue: Parma: Ducale Teatro Di Parma
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1840-1841
    Publication City and Publisher: Parma: Stamperia Carmignani
  - Pia de'Tolomei, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Performance Season/Date: La Primavera 1839
  - Poliuto, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Performance City and Venue: Napoli: Piazza Municipio
    Publication City and Publisher: Napoli: Stabilimento Musicale T. Cottrau
  - La Regina di Golconda, 1842 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Performance City and Venue: Roma: Teatro Valle
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1842
    Publication City and Publisher: Roma: Tipografia Puccinelli a Corre Sanguigna
  - La Regina di Golconda, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Coi Tipi di Francesco Lucca
  - La Regna di Golconda (La Reina de Golconda), 1859 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Performance City and Venue: Barcelona: El Gran Teatro del Liceo
    Performance Season/Date: 1859
    Publication City and Publisher: Barcelona: Imprenta y Libreria Politecnica de Tomas Gorcus
  - Roberto Devereaux, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Librettist: Cammarano, Salvatore
    Performance Season/Date: L'Autunno 1839
  - Roberto Devereaux, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Performance City and Venue: Parma: Ducale Teatro di Parma
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1840
    Publication City and Publisher: Parma: Presso Filippo Carmignani
  - Torquato Tasso, 1834 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Librettist: Ferretti, Giacopo
  - Ugo, Conte di Parigi [1 of 2], 1831 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Librettist: Sanquirico, Alessandro
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1831-1832
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: G. Truffi e Comp.
  - Ugo, Conte di Parigi [2 of 2], 1831 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Librettist: Sanquirio, Alessandro
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Per G. Truffi e Comp.
- Series XXIV: Faccio
  - Amleto, 1870 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - I Profughi Fiamminghi, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Librettist: Praga, Emilio
    Performance Season/Date: L'Autunno 1863
- Series XXV: Flotow
  - Martha or the Fair at Richmond, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Librettist: Riese, Friedrich Wilhelm
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: Charles F. Tretbar
  - Martha or the Fair at Richmond, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Series XXVI: Franchetti
  - Asrael, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Librettist: Fontana, Ferdinando
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Lent 1887-1888
  - Germania, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Librettist: Parravicini, A.; Rota, F.; Sala, L.; Songa, G.
    Performance Season/Date: La Primavera 1902
- Series XXVII: Gluck
  - Armida, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Librettist: Quinault, Philippe
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Stucchi, Ceretti & C.
  - Orfeo e Euridice, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Translator and Editor: Maggioni, Manfredo
    Performance City and Venue: London: Royal Italian Opera, Covent Garden
    Publication City and Publisher: London: J. Miles & Co.
- Series XXVIII: Gnaga
  - Swarten, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Performance City: Milano
    Performance Date: 1893
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Tip. della Stabilimento di E. Sonzogno
- Series XXIX: Gomez
  - Fosca, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Stabilimento Musicale Ditta F. Lucca
  - Il Guarany, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Librettist: Scalvini, Antonio
  - Il Guarany, 1871 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Performance City and Venue: Firenze: Regio Teatro Della Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: L'Autunno 1871
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Stabilimento Musicale Di F. Lucca
  - Salvator Rosa (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: R. Stabilimento Musicale Ricordi
- Series XXX: Gounod
  - Faust, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Librettist: Barbier, Jules; Carre, Michel
  - Faust, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: A. Barion
  - Saffo, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Librettist: Fontana
    Performance City and Venue: Covent Garden, The Royal Italian Opera
    Publication City and Publisher: Rupert Street, Haymarket: T. Brettell
- Series XXXI: Halevy
  - L'ebrea, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Performance City and Venue: Venezia: Teatro Malibran
    Performance Season/Date: L'Estate 1872
  - La Regina di Cipro, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Date: 1883
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Stabilimento di Edoardo Sonzogno
- Series XXXII: Hinrichs
  - Onti-Ora, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Librettist: Toland, M.B.M.
- Series XXXIII: Lalo
  - Le Roi D'ys, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Publication City and Publisher: Paris: Au Menestrel
- Series XXXIV: Leoncavallo
  - La Boheme, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    Librettist: Leoncavallo, Ruggero
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Edoardo Sonzogno
  - Pagliacci, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Publication City and Publisher: Napoli: C. Cirillo
  - La Reginetta delle Rose, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Librettist: Forzano
    Performance City and Venue: Milano: Casa Musicale Lorenzo Sonzogno